Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records ALBA.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Spanish Civil War Materials, 1933-1946
  - Subseries I:B: Subject Files, 1936-1940
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Rehabilitation, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Rehabilitation, journal, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Relatives of American Prisoners in Franco Spain, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Shipments to Spain, Documents, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: White, David McKelvy, undated, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Women's Committee, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Friends of the Garibaldi Brigade, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - International Brigades: "Commissars, The Tasks and Duties of", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - International Brigades: Leaflets, undated, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - International Brigades: Rosters (Photocopy), 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - International Brigades: "XV Brigade: One Year of Battle", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - International Volunteers: Maison des Blesses pour les Volontaires, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Lawyers Committee on American Relations with Spain, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Leaflets I, undated, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Leaflets II, undated, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Leaflets (photocopies), 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Appeals, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Bulletins, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Bulletins, undated, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Chapters, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Chapters, Manhattan, undated, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Children's Cities Campaign, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Emergency Committee, Vincent Sheean-Dinner, undated, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Executive Committee, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Financial Reports, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Press Releases, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Relief Ship, undated, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Reports, undated, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Trade Union Department, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Memorials, undated, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Minister of Defense: Documents, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - National Joint Committee for Spanish Relief, undated, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Negro People's Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Neutrality Act, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Newsletters: Fragments, undated, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters: The Granen Griper, draft, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Newsletters: International Brigades, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, undated, 1936, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Bulletin, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: "The Crime of Francisco Franco", undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Events and Fundraising, undated, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Washington Friends of Spanish Democracy, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy: Youth Committee, Bulletin, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Plan of Work (Commissar's Notes), c.1936-1938 (Box 8, Folder 9a)
    - Pope, Appeal to the, undated, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Prisoners: International Brigades, undated, 1938, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Prisoners: International Volunteers, Conference, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Prisoners: Women of Rieucros, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Prisoners of War: U.S. State Department, correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Radio Broadcasts: Transcripts, undated, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Reports from the Field, undated, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Reports from the Field: Burns, Paul, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Reports from the Field: Notebooks, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Reports from the Field: Orders of the Day, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Reports from the Field: Prisoners, undated, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Reports from the Field: Transport, Paris to Spain, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Sociedades Hispanas Confederades, undated, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Socorro Rojo Internacional: Prints and Pamphlets, undated (Box 8, Folder 22a)
    - Songs, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Songs: "No Pasaran," etc., 1937 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Spain: Aid, American Organizations, undated, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Spain: Aid, International, undated, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Spain: Canadian Blood Transfusion Unit, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Spain: "A Case Study," Propaganda Analysis, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Spain: "The Elections of 1936", undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Spain: Sketches (photocopies), undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Spanish Children, 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Spanish Children: Foster Parents, undated, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Spanish Children: School Notebooks, undated, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Spanish Children's Milk Fund, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Spanish Committee in Defense of Democracy: Publicity Department, undated, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Bulletin, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Children, undated, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Correspondence, undated, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Fundraising, undated, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Fundraising, Gypsy Rose Lee, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: International Conference for Aid to the Spanish Refugees, Report, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Manual, The Pilot, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Press Releases and Statements, undated, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Psychological Effects of War, Dinner Discussion, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Reports, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign: Trade Union Committee, undated, 1937-1938 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Spanish Refugees, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Spanish Refugees: Continental Conference, Mexico, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Spanish Refugees: Fleeing Barcelona, Draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Spanish Refugees: France, undated, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Spanish Refugees: Greater New York Committee to Save, undated, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Spanish Refugees: Helen Hayes, undated, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Spanish Refugees: Erika Mann, correspondence, Mar 1939-May 1939 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Spanish Refugees: Medical Aid Committee, undated, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Spanish Refugees: National Emergency Conference, New York, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Theater Arts Committee for Spain: The Spanish Play, by Kenneth White, ca.1936 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Trade Union Relief for Spain, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Series II: General Files, 1940-2006
  This series contains correspondence, subject files, writings, office files, clippings and ephemera that document the lives of individual veterans, the activities of VALB Posts, and the myriad causes and concerns of VALB membership over the years. The correspondence files, which include official VALB correspondence as well as announcements and appeals, and the office files provide an overview of the activities and concerns of the veterans from 1950-2000. Subjects with especially rich documentation include anniversary celebrations, commemorations and reunions; anti-Franco protests; political movements and political prisoners in Spain; and VALB's struggles with the House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC).
  Of special note are the Alvah Bessie, Heart of Spain correspondence files (1949-1953). The correspondence predominantly relates to the publication of a VALB anthology. Bessie's letters, especially those to and from Moe Fishman, also provide rich commentary on politics and the lives of several veterans.
  Materials added to this series in 2017 include of files from the VALB Chicago post. These files contain clippings, programs, flyers, and photos from special events organized by the Chicago post of the VALB between 1995 and 2003. They document anniversary celebrations, memorials, exhibitions, speeches, and lectures. Among these materials are articles, plays, and transcripts of speeches reflecting on the memories of veterans. Included in the Chicago Post files is binder of biographical data on volunteers from the Chicago area that contains information such as name, age, date of birth, date of departure to Spain, vocation, education, and political party affiliation. Data is recorded on one-page forms, which are arranged alphabetically by volunteer name.
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), 1977-1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ALBA: Exhibit, "Shouts From the Wall", 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - ALBA: Fredericka Martin Medical Archives, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - ALBA: Moscow Archives, undated, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ALBA: Photographs, Catalogues, undated, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Accion Republicana Española, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Activities and Events: Dinners and Dances, 1940-1981 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Activities and Events: Memorial Services, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Activities and Events: Rallies and Protests, undated, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Activities and Events: Symposiums and Lectures, undated, 1966-1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Alexander, William: 35th Division Postcard, undated (Box 10, Folder 10a)
  - Allan, Ted: "The Battle for Spain" ( Colliers), 1945 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Allen, Victor (Pulkkinen), undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - American Committee for a Free Spanish Republic, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - American Committee for the Protection for the Foreign Born, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - American Committee to Save Refugees, undated, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Action Committee, undated, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Artists and Scientists Division, undated, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Correspondence, Albert Einstein, Nov 1945 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Correspondence, Bishop Lewis O. Hartman, 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Financial Statements, 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Financial Statements, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Interfaith Division, 1942, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Minutes, 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom: Statements, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Amery, Al, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Anniversaries: General, undated, 1945-1973 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Anniversaries: Programs, 1974-1999 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Anniversaries: Tickets, 1958-1995 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Anniversary: 10th: Journal, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Anniversary: 15th: Journal, [1952] (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Anniversary: 25th, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Anniversary: 30th, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Anniversary: 34th, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Anniversary: 40th, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Anniversary: 40th, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Anniversary: 41st, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Anniversary: 42nd, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Anniversary: 45th, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Anniversary: 46th, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Anniversary: 47th, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Anniversary: 50th, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Anniversary: 50th, Bay Area Post, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Anniversary: 50th, Bay Area Post, Gala Sponsors, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Anniversary: 50th, Bay Area Post, Theater Program (Ed Asner), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Anniversary: 50th, Bay Area Post, Theater Program (Ring Lardner, Jr. script), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Anniversary: 50th: Clippings, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Anniversary: 50th: Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Anniversary: 50th: medal, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Anniversary: 51st, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Anniversary: 54th, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary: 56th, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary: 60th, 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary: 60th: Clippings, undated, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary: 63rd, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Franco, undated, 1945-1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Anti-Franco: Americans for Civic Action, undated, ca.1945 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Franco: Bulletins, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Franco: Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1961, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Anti-Franco: Demonstrations, undated, 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Franco: Madrid Pact, undated, 1948-1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Anti-Franco: Madrid Pact, Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Anti-Franco: Madrid Pact, "Materials Kit for Work on Spain", ca.1975 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Anti-Franco: Mayor of Madrid, protest, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Anti-Franco: Publications, France, 1948, ca.1960 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Anti-Franco: United Nations, 1945, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Anti-Franco: United Nations, Statement by Juliusz Katz-Suchy, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Anti-Franco: Wisconsin, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Anti-Franco: World Council of Churches, undated, 1948, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Anti-Franco: World's Fair, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Azcarate, Manuel: "Spain in the Present European and International Conjuncture", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Bailey, Bill, undated, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Bailey, Bill: The Odyssey of the Morning Star, I (1-179), undated, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Bailey, Bill: The Odyssey of the Morning Star, II (180-354), undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Bailey, Bill: The Odyssey of the Morning Star, III (355-472), undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Bailey, Bill: The Odyssey of the Morning Star, IV (473-641, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Barr, Rubin: Prelude, I (1-196), undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Barr, Rubin: Prelude, II (197-403), undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Barsky, Edward, 1954, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Bean, Adelaide: Who Fights This Battle?(script, originally presented 1936), 1997 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Bean, Adelaide: Interview, transcript, 1974, 1985, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Berch, Victor, undated, 1971-1998 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Bessie, Alvah, undated, 1950-1962 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Book Reviews, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Copyright, undated, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Correspondence, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Correspondence, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Correspondence, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Correspondence, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Correspondence, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Correspondence, Lillian Hellman, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, I (typescript, draft), undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, II, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, III, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, IV, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, V, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Bibliography, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Introduction--Dorothy Parker, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Materials, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Materials, Not Used, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Preface, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Prospectus, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Heart of Spain, Table of Contents, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Men in Battle, undated, 1939, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Bessie, Alvah: The Volunteers, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Blair, John Clarence Alvie, 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Books: Publicity Material, Notes and Correspondence, undated, 1968, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Books: Reviews, undated, 1939-1995 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Bottcher, Herman, 1944-1945, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Bottcher, Herman: Tribute, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Bown, Vernon: Bombing Case, 1955, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Brandeis University, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Brent, Jack, undated, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Burton, H. Ralph, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Canadian Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1971-1973, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Committee for a Democratic Spain: Amnista, 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Canut, Guillermo Mesque, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Carillo, Santiago, undated, 1969, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Carlson, Evans T., 1946 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Carsmen, Sam: Manuscript, Draft, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Casals, Pablo and Marta: Correspondence, 1957, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Central America, 1981, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Centre d'Estudis d'Historia Contemporania (Barcelona), undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Chaiken, George, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cogswell, Theodore, 1975-1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Collado, Thomas Diaz, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Commemorations, undated, 1942-2003 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Commemorations: 50th Anniversary, Exhibit--Italy, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Commemorations: Asociacion de Aviadores de la Republica, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Commemorations: Berlin, undated, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Commemorations: City College, undated, 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Commemorations: Dartmouth College, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Commemorations: German Democratic Republic, 1961, 1968, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Commemorations: German Democratic Republic, Clippings, 1961, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Commemorations: Ireland, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Commemorations: Jewish Memorial, correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Commemorations: International Brigades, Communist Party of Spain, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Commemorations: MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, undated, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Commemorations: Mataro, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Commemorations: Memorial Day Encampment, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Commemorations: Memorial Services, undated, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Commemorations: Memorials, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Commemorations: Monument, Barcelona, undated, 1983-1988, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Commemorations: Pennsylvania State University, Address--Robert Colodny, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Commemorations: Paul Robeson, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Commemorations: Spain, 50th Anniversary, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Commemorations: Spain, 60th Anniversary, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Commemorations: Sweden, undated, 1961, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Commemorations: Union des Anciens Resistants Juifs de Belgique (Belgium), 1989 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Commemorations: Wisconsin, Madison, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1967, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Committees: Speakers Committee, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Conference: American Continental Congress, Mexico, undated, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Conference: Asian-Pacific Peace Conference, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Conference: Canada, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Conference: Congreso Internacional de Mujeres, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Conference: Congreso Latino Americano de Juventades, undated (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Conference: Convention of Solidarity, Mexico, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Conference: Italy, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Conference: Panamericana de Solidaridad, undated (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Conference: Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB), National, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Conference: VALB, National, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Conference: VALB, National, undated (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Conference: The Worker in Spain Today, Canada, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Conference: "World Congress of Jewish Volunteers Who Fought in Spain," Israel, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Constitutions (VALB), 1939, 1941, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence: Announcements and Appeals, Friends, 1950-1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Announcements and Appeals, Veterans, 1938-1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Announcements and Appeals, Veterans, 1950-1959 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Announcements and Appeals, Veterans, 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Announcements and Appeals, Veterans, 1970-2000 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Announcements and Appeals, Veterans, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1959 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 20)